A Guide to the Records of Virginia Tech Dining Services, 1994-2013
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Records of Virginia Tech Dining Services, 1994-2013
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 8/2/1j
9.71 Cubic Feet; 17 boxes
The Records of Virginia Tech Dining Services comprise award submission scrapbooks for events and dinners hosted by the Dining Services department of the Division of Student Affairs that were compiled and submitted for awards from 1994 through 2013. A 2009 schematic design for the food court Turner Place at Lavery Hall is also included.
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Division of Student Affairs. Dining Services
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Source of Acquisition
The Records of Virginia Tech Dining Services were transferred to Special Collections and University Archives in 2014.
Administrative History
The Dining Services department of Virginia Tech is a part of the Division of Student Affairs (DSA). It was previously known as the Culinary Services department and the Dining Programs department as well as being combined with what is now the Housing and Residence Life department, also within the DSA.
Scope and Content
The Records of Virginia Tech Dining Services primarily comprise award submission scrapbooks for events and dinners hosted by the Dining Services department of the Division of Student Affairs that were compiled and submitted for awards from 1994 through 2013. Awards include the the National Association of College and University Food Services's Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Most Innovative Nutrition Program Contest, and Vegetarian Marketplace Competition as well as Cuisine Creators' Vegan Recipe Contest and Most Creative Nutrition Month Promotion. A 2009 schematic design for the food court Turner Place at Lavery Hall is also included.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by type of material.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Archival Material
Materials related to Virginia Tech Dining Services, including information about dining halls, are in the Record Group Vertical Files.
Separated Material
The following items were transferred to the Rare Book Collection:
Student Employee Handbook: In Step with Culinary Services. [Blacksburg, Va.: Residential and Dining Program, 1992].
What's Cooking / Virginia Tech Culinary Services. Vol. III, No. 12 (Nov. 11/17, 1991), Call no. LD 5655 .A781 R4 W53
The Grapevine / Virginia Tech Culinary Services, Call no. LD 5655 .A781 R4 G73
Vol. I, No. 15 (May. 28/June 3, [no year])
Vol. I, No. 19 (June 25/July 1, [no year])
Vol. I, No. 20 (July 2/8, [no year])
Vol. I, No. 22 (July 16/22, [no year])
In Touch: Keeping Faculty and Staff in Touch with Virginia Tech / Virginia Tech Culinary Services
Undated [November 1991?]
December 1991
January 1992
Rights Statement for Archival Description
The guide to the Records of Virginia Tech Dining Services by Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, is licensed under a CC0 (https://creativecommons.org/share-your- work/public-domain/cc0/).
Index Terms
Subjects:
University Archives; University History
Organizations:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Division of Student Affairs. Dining Services; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Series I: Plans and designs
  - Virginia Tech Academic and Student Affairs Building [Turner Place at Lavery Hall] Schematic Design, 2009 (Box 1)
- Series II: Award and contest submission scrapbooks
  - Subseries A: The National Association of College and University Food Services
    - "Road Trip!", entry 1L15, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Theme Dinner category, 2008 (Box 1)
    - "Puttin' on the Ritz", Residence Hall Dining - Special Event/Theme Dinner award category, 1997 (Box 2)
    - "West End Market", Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Specialty Restaurant or "Shop" category, 1999 (Box 2)
    - "Virginia Tech's Farms & Fields Project: Promoting a Sustainable Food System", entry 6L12, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Retail Sales - Single Stand-Alone Concept/Outlet category, 2010 (Box 2)
    - [Deet's Place "Travelogue"], Specialty Restaurant or "Shop" award category, 1994 (Box 3)
    - "Catering Into the Next Millennium", entry 6L3, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Catering - Special Event category, 1999 (Box 3)
    - "Chef Series Premier Event: Valentine's Day in Manhattan, February 14, 2003", entry 2L19, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Special Event/Theme Dinner category, 2003 (Box 4)
    - "D2: Taking Traditional Dining to the Next Level", entry 3L5, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Multiple Concepts/Outlets category, 2005 (Box 4)
    - "Virginia Tech Hokie Outback Challenge, April 26: Outeat, Outplay, Outlast", Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Special Event/Theme Dinner category, 2002 (Box 5)
    - "A Valentine's Voyage: Friday, February 13, 2004", entry 2L14, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Special Event/Theme Dinner category, 2004 (Box 5)
    - "Personal Touch Catering presents the Greatest Show on Campus", Catering - Standard Menu award category, 1998 (Box 6)
    - "The Greatest Show on Campus presented by Personal Touch Catering", Catering - Special Event award category, 1998 (Box 6)
    - "Blue Ridge Barbecue", entry 5L9, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Retail Sales - Single Stand-Alone Concept/Outlet category, 2002 (Box 6)
    - "Nutrition: From the Ground Up", Most Innovative Nutrition Program Contest, 2010 (Box 7)
    - "Virginia Harvest Celebration, Tuesday, September 14, 2010", entry 2L23, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residential Dining - Special Event category, 2011 (Box 7)
    - "D2: Art Show, April 21, 2005", entry 1L37, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Theme Dinner category, 2006 (Box 8)
    - "Captain Growley's Pirate Adventure: September 19, 2006, Shultz Dining Center", entry 1L35, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Theme Dinner category, 2007 (Box 8)
    - "Bon Voyage! Wednesday, April 21, 1999", entry 2L23, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Special Event/Theme Dinner category, 2000 (Box 9)
    - "Dietrick Dining Center", entry 3L5, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Multiple Concepts/Outlets category, 2010 (Box 9)
    - "Frank's Deli", entry 5L4, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Retail Sales - Single Stand-Alone Concept/Outlet category, 2004 (Box 10)
    - "Hawaiian Luau", Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Theme Dinner category, 2005 (Box 10)
    - "New River Valley Wine Association Dinner, Spring 2004", entry 4L14, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Catering - Special Event category, 2004 (Box 11)
    - "Hollywood Night, entry 5L18, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Theme Dinner category, 2005 (Box 11)
    - "Tis the Season…", Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residential Dining - Special Event category, 2012 (Box 12)
    - "Turner Place at Lavery Hall", entry 4L10, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Retail Sales - Multiple Concepts/Marketplace category, 2013 (Box 12)
    - "Tastes of Las Vegas, March 5, 2006", entry 5L13 (2 books), Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Catering - Special Event category, Bronze Winner, 2006 (Box 13)
    - "Southern Nights", entry 1L26, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Theme Dinner category, 2007 (Box 13)
    - "Medieval Feast & Faire", entry 5L8, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Catering - Special Event category, 2008 (Box 13)
    - "Seasons of Change", Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Catering - Special Event category, 2010 (Box 13)
    - "Simply the Best: A Star-Studded Evening, Thursday, April 23, During Dinner in the Depot at Dietrick and Shultz Dining Centers", Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Special Event/Theme Dinner category, 1999 (Box 14)
    - "Interviewing Over Dinner: Rare, Medium or Well Done?", entry 4M9, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Catering - Special Event category, 2001 (Box 14)
    - "We Know Beans!: Vegetarian Bean College, February 3-21, 2003, The Depot at Dietrick", Vegetarian Marketplace Competition, 2002 (Box 14)
    - "Breakfast at Brennan's", entry 1L14, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Theme Dinner category, 2008 (Box 14)
    - "Dinner on the Titanic", entry 2L1, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residential Dining - Special Event category, 2013 (Box 15)
    - "Alice in Wonderland", Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residential Dining - Special Event category, 2011 (Box 15)
    - "Bowl Dynasty", entry 5L8, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Retail Sales - Single Stand-Alone Concept/Outlet category, 2001 (Box 16)
    - "Chef Series Cookbook", entry 2L13, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Special Event/Theme Dinner category, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "A World's Fair", entry 1L27, Loyal E. Horton Dining Awards, Residence Hall Dining - Theme Dinner category, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Photocopies of entry forms with judges' ratings and comments sheets, 2004-2008 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Subseries B: Cuisine Creators
    - "Best Bites: Get a taste for nutrition!", Most Creative Nutrition Month Promotion Contest, 2005 (Box 16)
    - "Tempeh and Bean Rancheros", Vegan Recipe Contest, Third Place, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 4)